JANET LEIGH CLARK janetleighclark@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

As an accomplished Instructional Designer and Web Generalist with over sixteen years of experience in educational technology, curriculum development, and web design, my passion lies with e-learning design and development. I have demonstrated the ability to employ technology to advance objectives in challenging and diverse environments. In addition I have excellent communication and problem solving skills, and a talent for integrating harmonious teams.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Monarch Media, April 2011-present

Senior Instructional Designer / Project Manager

- Instructional design for a variety of e-learning approaches including: adaptive paths, branching scenarios, experiential learning, gamification, social media and user generated content (UGC), behavioral modeling videos, video interactions, and others
- Instructional design for the deaf and hard of hearing community including video and animation scripting and development
- Educating teams on instructional design methods and best practices for e-learning
- Project management of e-learning courses, LMS implementation and web site development
- Coordinating and leading international teams including both full time employees and contractors
- Client consultations, needs assessments, concept presentations
- Facilitator for usability testing of mobile apps and responsive designs
- Accessibility design and enforcement of 508 compliance where needed
- Reporting for evidence base studies including quantitative and qualitative analysis
- Technologies include: Articulate Studio, Articulate Storyline, Moodle LMS, Adobe Captivate, Wordpress CMS, html, css, Camtassia, Adobe Creative Suite and much more
- Clients include: Autodesk, Boston Public Health Department, California Safe Routes to School, Cengage Learning, College Board, Covidien, ETR Associates, Health Net, McGraw Hill, pepnet.org, San Francisco Public Health Department, Stanford Graduate School of Business, U.S. Farm Bureau, World Bank, and others. Additional project partnerships funded through Small Business Innovation Grants (SBIR) and the National Institute of Health (NIH)

Freelance Contractor - Jan Clark Design, 2009-2010

Instructional Designer / Web Designer and Developer / Content Writer

- Instructional design for online and live courses
- Writing summative assessments
- Web design and development
- Marketing communications

- Presentation development
- Ghost writing

Fair Isaac Corporation, 1997-2009

Education Lead / Desktop Education Manager

- Writing manuals/workbooks for customized employee training distributed in both print matter and through the company intranet
- Design and development of online learning programs
- Design and development of database to track employee training resulting in better communication to management and a better understanding of spending
- Design and development of internal Employee University deployed on corporate intranet
- Delivery of both in-person and remote live classes to employees
- Supervision of Desktop Education team and external contractors
- Technologies used include: Authorware, Adobe Captivate, Articulate Studio, Adobe Director (Macromedia), Adobe Flash (Macromedia), Camtassia, Microsoft Access, InfoPath, SharePoint, Visio, MS Project, html, css, and more

CMC Personnel, (on contract to Fair Isaac) 1996-1997

Graphic Designer

- Create PowerPoint presentations for annual conference
- Layout and preparation for conference binder
- Create custom MS Word templates to support corporate branding initiatives
- Write manual on template use to support branding initiative

EDUCATION

- California State University Monterey Bay BS in Communication Design/Web Design
- Cabrillo College AS in Web Media
- Santa Rosa Junior College Human Resources Coursework
- San Francisco State University Multimedia Studies Program

Additional Professional Development achieved through ongoing use of webinars and attendance at conferences offered through ASTD and eLearning Guild.

I have been selected to present a concurrent session at the US Distance Learning Association Conference in May 2014, plus a poster session on a different topic at the same conference.

*Accepted to CSUMB Fall 2014 for the Masters in Instructional Science and Technology Degree